<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Act additional to the proclamation for the more easie and effectual in-bringing of the pole-money. At Edinburgh, the eight day of October, 1698.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05269</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1354A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R184019</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">53299246</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 53299246</idno>
            <idno type="VID">179983</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05269)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 179983)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2810:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Act additional to the proclamation for the more easie and effectual in-bringing of the pole-money. At Edinburgh, the eight day of October, 1698.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
                  <author>Scotland. Sovereign (1694-1702 : William II)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the heirs and successors of Andrew Anderson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1698</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Title vignette: royal seal with initials W R (?).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Poll tax --  Law and legislation --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:179983:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 7 -->
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <p>W R</p>
                  <p>DIEV ET MON DROIT</p>
                  <p>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</p>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>
               <hi>ACT</hi> Additional to the Proclamation for the more eaſie and effectual In-bringing of the <hi>Pole-money.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>At Edinburgh, <date>the eight day of October, 1698.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>The Lords of His Majeſties Privy Council underſtanding, that <hi>William Cochran</hi> of <hi>Ferguſlies,</hi> Tackſman of the two Poles, impoſed in the laſt Seſſion of Parliament, hath not as yet found Caution, conform to the Articles and Minut of Roup ſubſcribed by him nor taken our his Tack, which he alſo ſubſcribed together with, and in preſence of the Lords of His Majeſties<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> The ſaury and Exchequer, upon the 17. and 19. <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ays of <hi>September</hi> laſt, whereby it may happen that the Commiſſioners of Supply in the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Shires appointed by the Act of parliament and the Proclamation of Council lately thereon emitted, to meet the ſecond <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>October</hi> inſtant, for dividing and diſtributing themſelves into ſeveral Diſtricts for taking up the Liſts of the poleable Perſons within their Bounds; <hi>As alſo,</hi> that the Magiſtrats of Burghs Royal appointed by the ſaid Act, to meet the third <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>October</hi> inſtant, and to take up Rolls and Liſts of the Poleable perſons within their reſpective Burghs, may be leſs carefull to meet and obſerve the foreſaid appointments, upon which nevertheleſs the effectual ingathering of the ſaid Pole ſo neceſſarly depends. <hi>Therefore</hi> and without pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice to the Obligements incumbent upon the ſaid <hi>William Cochran</hi> of <hi>Ferguſlie,</hi> by Vertue of the ſaid Minut of Roupe and Tack of the poles ſubſcribed by him, as ſaid is, both for finding ſufficient Caution and making due payment of the Tack-duty contained in the ſaid Tack: But for His Majeſties greater Security as to the payment of the foreſaid Pole, which ſo ſpecially concerns His Majeſtys Service, for the Ends and Uſes to which theſe Poles are deſtinat and appropriat: <hi>The Lords</hi> of His Majeſties Privy Council, have thought fit to Require and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, and do hereby moſt ſtrictly and peremptorly <hi>Require</hi> and <hi>Command</hi> the foreſaid Commiſſioners of Shires, and Magiſtrats of Burghs who <unclear>ſhall not</unclear> duely keep the foreſaid Meetings, upon the ſecond and third <hi>Tueſdays of October</hi> inſtant, and obſerve and do therein as is ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the foreſaid Act of Parliament and proclamation, That they keep their ſaid Meetings and perform the Appointments thereof, at leaſt betwixt and the laſt <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>October</hi> inſtant, and whither the ſaid <hi>Ferguſlie</hi> or any from him attend the ſaid Meeting or not. <hi>Viz.</hi> The ſaid Commiſſioners of Shires for Dividing and Diſtributing themſelves into the ſaid Diſtricts, for taking up the Liſts and Rolls of poleable perſons within their Bounds, conform to the Act of parliament upon the firſt <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>November</hi> next, and the ſaids Magiſtrats of Burghs for taking up and making the ſaids Liſts and Rolls of poleable perſons within their Burghs conform to the ſaid Act, and to the effect the rema<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent Orders and Appointments contained in the ſaid Act and proclamation for payment of the ſaid pole, may be punctually obſerved as Ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feirs; And the Sheriffs and Stewarts of the reſpective Shires and Stewartries and their Deputs, are hereby in like manner required and commanded to make timeous Intimation of theſe preſents to the Commiſſioners for their Subſidiarie Meeting in manner above-appointed; As likewiſe that Advertiſement be timeouſly given to the Commiſſioners abſent and appointed to particular Diſtricts, and that Intimation be made at the ſeveral paroch Churches within the Shires upon the Sabbath immediatly preceeding the firſt <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>November,</hi> of the parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular places to which the poleable perſons are to repair for giving in their Degrees, Characters and Qualities, according to which they are polled under the pains contained in the ſaid Act of parliament, certifying ſuch of the ſaid Commiſſioners as ſhall not meet and keep the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Subſidiary Meetings in caſe of failȝie of the ſaid firſt Meeting upon the ſecond <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>October inſtant,</hi> or that ſhall not keep and attend the Diſtrict to be to them appointed, for taking up the Liſts and Rolls of the ſaid poleable perſons, they ſhall be conveened before the Lords of His Majeſties privy Council to be puniſhed for their ſaid neglect and contempt; And the ſaid Sheriffs and Stewarts and their Deputs are hereby required and commanded under the ſame Certification to return to the Clerks of privy Council, the Names of the ſaids Commiſſioners who ſhall fail in their foreſaid Duties hereby enjoyned, and that betwixt and the fifteenth day of <hi>November</hi> next: <hi>As alſo,</hi> certifying the ſaid Magiſtrats of Burghs who ſhall fail in their Duty of the premiſſes, that they ſhall be puniſhed in like manner; And the ſaid Lords of His Majeſties privy Council, do further again peremptorly require and Command the foreſaid former proclamation and Act of Parliament anent the pole-money to be punctually obſerved and obeyed as to the taking up of the ſaid Liſts and Rolls of poleable-perſons, and making complea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting and returning the Books thereof, and in the whole remanent Heads and points thereof, and that theſe preſents be immediatly publiſhed at the Mercat Croſs of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and that His Majeſties Solicitor do inſtantly cauſe print and tranſmit Coppies hereof to the ſeveral Sheriffs and Stuarts and their Deputs, for due publication and Intimation to be made of the ſame with all Diligence.</p>
            <p>Extracted by me</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>GILB. ELIOT.</hi> Cls. Sti. Concilii.</signed>
               <lb/>
God Save the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the Heirs and Succeſſors of <hi>Andrew Anderſon</hi> Printer to the King's moſt Excellent Majeſty, <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1698.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
